# **EMAN ALAJRAMI**

### PhD student- UWL

Alajrami.eman@gmail.com

0044787619634

Gaza, Palestine

in / in/eman-alajrami-48906776

## Personal Profile —

I consider myself a hardworking person, self-motivated, committed and organized. I have **CIAgile** Certified Professional and **OCP**, and I have been working in the **academic fields** related to computer science for more than ten years. I have a significant commitment to keep learning and developing my professional skills. I'm also very good at working as part of a team and individually. I enjoy solving challenging research problems. I have good knowledge and skills in Information Retrieval and a good background in AI, Machine Learning, and deep learning. In addition, I have an excellent understanding of **UML and Object-Oriented Modeling.** 

#### Skills -

**Development Skills** 

C, C++, JAVA, & Python

**UML Modelling and Design** 

HTML, CSS, JavaScript & Php

**Iterative Prototyping** 

**Quality Assurance** 

**Usability Testing** 

**Accessibility, Inclusive Design** 

## **Employment History**

09/2017 - 01/2021

Head of Multimedia Department

Faculty of IT, the University of Palestine – Gaza, Palestine

**Job responsibilities**: Providing academic leadership for staff, taking responsibility for helping to determine the strategic direction of the department. And also developing the process of teaching and learning. In addition, creating and fostering relationships with appropriate external agencies for promotion and marketing purposes.

09/2009 – Current

## Computing Lecturer (Full Time)

Faculty of IT, the University of Palestine – Gaza, Palestine

**Job responsibilities**: Teaching computer science modules for undergraduate students at the faculty of IT. Courses I taught are: Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms analysis, Information Retrieval, Information Security, Databases in SQL and OEACLE, System Analysis and Design and Software Engineering.

09/2009 – Current

Computing Lecturer (Part Time)

Faculty of IT, Alguds Open University, Gaza -Palestine

**Job responsibilities:** Teaching computer science modules for undergraduate students at the faculty of IT. Courses I taught are: Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms analysis, Visual Programming and Office Automation.

09/2010 – 06/2012

Computing Lecturer (Part Time)

Faculty of IT, Gaza University, Gaza -Palestine

**Job responsibilities:** Teaching computer science modules for undergraduate students. Courses I taught are Programming, Data Structures, System Analysis and Design.

01/2008-09/2008

Web Administrator and Content Manager

The Palestinian International Campaign to End Gaza Siege, Gaza, Palestine

**Job responsibilities:** Managing and updating of the web contents, Web design using Adobe Photoshop, PHP web programming, Report writing using Microsoft office applications.

10/2002-07/2005

**Teaching Assistant** 

The Islamic University of Gaza, Gaza, Palestine

**Job responsibilities** Courses I tough: Lab section for programming, Data Structure, Operating Systems, Computer Graphics, Introduction to computer science.

#### **Education** –

2010 - 2012

B.Eng: Software Engineering (GPA: 95.29%)

University of Palestine, Palestine

Graduated in Top 2% of Class- I was the Top-ranked student. Received a scholarship of Excellence from the university



**Modules attended**: Requirement Engineering, Introduction to Software Engineering, Software Testing, Programming, Human-Computer Interaction, Neural Networks, Software Project management, Formal methods, Software Quality Assurance.

Graduation Project: "Designing and developing an Intelligent Tutoring System to teach OOP" with a team of four students.

2005 - 2007

## MSc. Computer Information Systems (GPA: 94.8%)

Arab Academy for Banking & Financial Sciences – Jordan

Graduated in Top 2% of Class - I was the Top raTop-rankednked student Recipient of the President Scholarship for Excellence 50% discount of tuition fees.

Coursework in Advanced Databases, Information Retrieval, Advanced Networking, Advanced AI, Advanced Multimedia, Information Systems Management, Advanced Software Engineering, Advanced Operating Systems, and Information Systems Security.

Thesis: "Hiding text into the greyscale image using steganography and cryptography principles".

1998 - 2002

### BSc. Computer Science (GPA: 85.22%)





Graduated in Top 2% of Class

Coursework in Math, OOP, AI, Statistics & Probability, Data Structures, Software Engineering, Computer Graphics, Operating Systems, Discrete Compilers Design Math, Distributed Systems, Databases, and Automata Theory.

Graduation Project: "C code Generator", a software that converts any flowchart to a c code generated as a text file using visual C++

#### **List of Publications -**

- 2019 Eman Alajrami, Belal A.M. Alashqar, Bassem S. Abu-Nasser, Ahmed J. Khalil, Musleh M.Musleh, Alaa M. Barhoom & S. S. Abu Naser, "Handwritten Signature Verification using Deep Learning", (IJAMR), Vol. 3 Issue 12, December 2019, Pages: 39-44
- Eman Alajrami, Bassem S. Abu-Nasser, Ahmed J. Khalil, Musleh M. Musleh, Alaa M. Barhoom & S. S. Abu Naser, "Blood Donation Prediction using Artificial Neural Network", 2019 International Journal of Academic Engineering Research (IJAER) 3 (10):1-7
- Alaa M. Barhoom, Samy S. Abu-Naser, Bassem S. Abu-Naser, Ahmed J. Khalil, Msleh H. Musleh, Eman Alajrami, "Predicting Liver Patients using Artificial Neural Network", 2019, (IJAISR) 3 (10):1-11
- Eman Alajrami, Hani Tabash, Yassir Singer, M.-T. El Astal, "On using Al-based human identification in improving surveillance system efficiency", a conference paper published in ICPET 2019, IEEE, 23th-24th October 2019.

2017	Mohammed Awad, Hisham Khdair, Eman Alajrami, Mohammed Manahi, "Selective Software Project Management Methodology", International Journal of Software & Hardware Research in Engineering, volume 5			
2015	Samy Abu Naser, Ihab Zaqout, Mahmoud Abu Ghosh, Rasha Atallah and Eman Alajrami, "Predicting Student Performance Using Artificial Neural Network: in the Faculty of Engineering and Information Technology", International Journal of Hybrid Information Technology,8(2),221-228. (ISI Cited Publication)			
2014	Elajrami E., AbuLamddi M., "Comparison between Vector Space Model and Fuzzy Set Model Retrieval for Arabic Collection", June 2014, IJRIM, volume4			

## Certifications -

03-2015	Agile Certified Professional (CIAgile)
---------	--

09-2004 Oracle Certified Professional (OCP)

# Workshops & Conferences —————

10-2019	Participation in the "International Conference on Promising Electronic Technologies
10-2013	(ICPET)", IEEE, organized by Palestine Technical College Deir El-Balah and Al-Azhar University
	– Gaza.

- O4-2013 Attending: The 4<sup>th</sup> Scientific Day "*Future Technology: Revolution, Applications, Privacy & Protection*", conducted on the 9<sup>th</sup> of Apr. 2013 by the faculty of Information Technology at The University of Palestine, Gaza-Palestine.
- 04-2012 Member of the Preparation committee for the 3<sup>rd</sup> Scientific Day "*Mobile Technology*", conducted on the 28<sup>th</sup> of Apr. 2012 by the faculty of Information Technology at The University of Palestine, Gaza-Palestine.
- 12-2008 **Participant:** "How to Choose a Major", participation on the First Scientific Day: "IT Theory & Practices", held at the university of Palestine

## Training Courses \_\_\_\_\_

- **07/2019** 50 hours training course in "*Data Science with Python*" at University of Palestine organize and sposored by iBridge and QIF from June 2019 to August 2019.
- 40 hours training course in "*Training Of Trainers (TOT) in Freelancing*" at Mercy Corps institute from Jul 2017 to Sep 2017.

02/2015	40 hours training course in " <i>Agile Certified Professional</i> " at Mercy Corps institute from Feb 2015 to Apr 2015.
06/2014	40 hours training course in " <b>Soft Skills in Academic plan</b> " at Mercy Corps institute from Jul 2014 to August 2014.
10/2013	60 hours training course in " <i>Preparation for Master and PhD scholarship</i> " including 40 hour for <b>IELTS</b> from 10/2013 to 12/2013 at Islamic University of Gaza.
03/2011	200 hours training course in "Palestinian Faculty Development Program (PFDP) English course" including 40 hours for TOEFL at AMIDEAST from 1/3/2010 to 1/3/2011.
05/2010	40 hours training course in ASP.NET Web Development: C# .NET Programming.
02/2005	40 hours training course in " <i>Linux Operating System (redhat 9)</i> " From 6/1/2005 to 17/2/2005 Held at The Future Training Center.
06/2003	120 hours training course in " <i>Oracle Certified Professional (OCP)</i> " from Jan 2003 to Jun 2003, held at Computer Land Center.

# References —

Dr. Rawia F. Radi	Eng. Ahmed I. Alastal	Dr. Iyad M. Alagha	
Assistant Professor	Salesforce Technical Architect	Associate Professor	
Dean of the Faculty of Information Technology	London Bluewolf- an IBM conpany	Head of Mobile Computing Department	
Faculty of Information Technology-	47 Marks Lane 3rd floor	Faculty of Information Technology, the Islamic University of Gaza, Palestine	
IUG, Palestine	London , UK		
	EC3R 7QQ	ialagha@iugaza.edu.ps	
rradi@iugaza.edu.ps	ahmed.alastal@ibm.com		
(.070)500700504		(+972)592542727	
(+970)592706591	(+44)7479511020		